Some missions need a hitman...others need a soldier.
Sicario: Day of the Soldado is a action, crime,
thriller film directed by Stefano Sollima.
Agent Matt Graver teams up with operative Alejandro Gillick to prevent Mexican drug
cartels from smuggling terrorists across the United States border.
Alejandro Gillick, played by Benicio del Toro.
Matt Graver, played by Josh Brolin.
Isabel Reyes, played by Isabela Merced.
Steve Forsing, played by Jeffrey Donovan.
Cynthia Foards, played by Catherine Keener.
Gallo, played by Manuel Garcia-Rulfo.
Sicario: Day of the Soldado (also known as Sicario 2: Soldado or simply Soldado) is a 2018 American
action crime thriller film directed by Stefano Sollima and written by Taylor Sheridan.
A sequel to 2015's Sicario, the film features Benicio del Toro, Josh Brolin, Jeffrey Donovan and Raoul Trujillo
reprising their roles, with Isabela Merced, Manuel Garcia-Rulfo and Catherine Keener joining the cast.
The story relates to human trafficking at the U.S.–Mexico border and a covert effort by the
United States government to incite increased conflict among the cartels.
Sicario: Day of the Soldado was released in the United States and Canada on June 29, 2018, by Sony Pictures Releasing under its Columbia Pictures
label, while it was distributed internationally by Lionsgate (excluding Latin America and Spain, where it was distributed by Sony).
The film is dedicated to the memory of Jóhann Jóhannsson, the composer of
the first film, who died four months before it came out.
It received generally favorable reviews from critics.
A sequel, titled Sicario: Capos, is in development.
The film explores themes of rescue, central intelligence agency
(cia), corruption, usa–mexico border, sequel.
The tone is dark and intense.